hey guys welcome to yoga with Adrien I'm
Adrian and today we have a sequence for
anxiety so this practice is awesome for
when you're feeling stressed out or
maybe you're feeling a little anxious
maybe a little panic attackyoutube
[Music]
let's begin in a nice comfortable
seat sit up nice and
tall and arrive here now you've started
the video you're here the hard part is
over let's begin with the breath inhale
as you breathe in draw the shoulders up
to the
ears as you breathe out draw the
shoulders down away from the
ears good as you breathe in squeeze and
lift and as you breathe out drop create
space couple more times inhale find what
feels good
here and exhale create
space one more time inhale squeeze to
the
Max and exhale create
space awesome take your right ear over
your right shoulder breathe ground down
through the
[Music]
elbows lift it back to Center and to the
other side left ear over left shoulder
draw down through the
[Music]
elbows great bringing it back to Center
and we're going to come into um a little
mudra here as we prepare for alternate
nostril breathing so this is my number
one if you don't have time for the whole
video at least have time for this uh
pranayama technique which I really do
think is like a magic Elixir for those
for when I'm feeling um anxious uh if
you ever feel like you are in a kind of
panic attack moment or anything like
that you just need to
d-stress balance out this is the one for
you my friends so we're going to take
the kind of hang loose sign here it's
kind of like this and we're just going
to bring it to the ring finger and the
thumb so you bring the the two piece
fingers in or if that's difficult for
you you can also do your middle finger
and your
thumb so we have your thumb and an extra
finger
here and we have a whole video on on
Alternate nostril breathing so if you're
new to this and you want to go ahead and
learn the technique first you can pause
it and click on that open it up in
another window and it's really
lovely um but to honor your time we're
just going to hop right in and so you
can practice this regularly so thumb's
going to come to the right nostril we
sit up nice and tall and breathe in
through the left
nostril keep the shoulders relaxed as
you pause at the top we switch covering
the left nostril breathing out through
the right
nostril inhale in through the right
nostril always holding pausing at the
top to switch exhale out through the
left nostril
inhale
in alternating at the top
exhale
inhale and alternating at the top exhale
keep it
going nice and easy smooth breaths
again alternating at the
top after a little bit of experiment you
find a rhythm that works good for you a
hand mudra that works good for you
on even and out here really
commit then gently release both hands
down take a deep breath in through both
nostrils and out through both
[Music]
nostrils slowly Open the
Eyes amazing and notice how you
feel great from here we're going to move
on to all fours but take this sense
whatever the breath did to you maybe
nothing but just take take one thing and
and add it on right so we're staying
present in the moment but we're kind of
allowing oursel to change the course of
things right trying to let go of the
stress the anxiety in the body that
breath so lovely for the nervous system
so keep it soft and easy as you come to
all fours here my sweet friends be kind
to
yourself and we'll move into a little
cat
Cow this should feel awesome we've
already connected the brain and the
breath in the alternate nostril
breathing narana it's a purifying breath
so keep nice long smooth deep breaths
here as you now begin to integrate the
spine which is also connected to the
brain so when the brain is a mess it is
so beneficial to do spinal work even
something is simple and delicious as cat
Cow
awesome from here I'm going to curl the
toes under Walk The Palms slightly
forward nice and easy inhale in on an
exhale lift the hips downward-facing dog
so connect to your strength here but
keep a softness press into the Palms
take care of the wrists bend the
knees inhale in exhale lowering back
down awesome press into the tops of the
feet walk the wrist back underneath the
shoulders then inhale keep the right
palm where it is here and we're going to
open the left fingertips out so just go
as far as you can before you feel uh a
pinch in the back body opening
inhale exhale left palm down right
fingertips reach up so it might not be
all the way here is what I'm trying to
say it might just be here or even here
as you inhale open up the the
chest
exhale again to the left inhale press
away from your yoga
mat exhale press into the tops of the
feet
inhale and exhale and one more
time long in the
neck synchronizing with the
breath super awesome all right right
walk the knees together take a child's
pose here go ahead and keep the
fingertips reaching out long though so
stretching through the side
body knees are together though and we
bow the
forehead rest your
heart now slowly we're going to walk the
Palms over towards the right excuse me
left edge of your mat and the right
hand's going to come over to um kiss the
left hand so maybe they come one on top
of each
other breathe into the right shoulder
the right side body pull back gently
with the right hip crease and breathe
deeply and now through
Center and to the right right palm to
the right edge of your mat left palm
comes and hops on top of the right and
we breathe here forehead grounding down
down reaching
down stick with your breath my friends I
know the mind is powerful but so is your
breath so come back to Center inhale
lifts you up exhale curl the toes under
downward facing dog okay time for a
cleanser we need it inhale in through
the nose exhale out through the mouth
inhale in through the
nose exhale out through the
mouth one more don't be shy beauty of
Home
practice Lion's
breath great drop the left heel lift the
right leg up high inhale exhale step it
up into a nice low
lunge prepping for Warrior 2 take your
time getting there we'll pivot on the
back foot keep the front knee bent when
you're ready rise up
strong find strong footing here today
super important that you ground through
all four corners of the feet press into
the knife edge of that back foot and
charge the left inner thigh reach the
right fingertips really reach left
fingertips back really reach breathe
deep here send energy out in all
directions left to right down to the
Earth and lift and length and up through
the crown big breath in here big breath
out draw your shoulders down pull the
pinkies
back great then keep the front knee bent
here for now as you reach the right
fingertips forward up and back Peaceful
Warrior here keep the front knee Bend
now hug the lower ribs in just a hair
sorry itch and then we're going to
inhale straighten the leg front leg
exhale
Bend inhale inhale
reach exhale
Bend one more inhale
reach exhale Bend this time continue the
journey all the way down extended side
angle right fingertips to the Earth left
fingertips Towards the Sky you can also
be here on the top of the thigh breathe
deep inhale
in Long exhale
out
inhale and and exhale stick with your
breath one more time inhale
in and exhale bringing the left
fingertips
down we'll pivot back to our lunge plant
The Palms step it back to plank you can
move through a vyasa here if you like or
send it straight to downward-facing dog
melt your heart back send your hips up
High Press into the Palms especially the
index finger and thumb
and we'll drop the right heel down and
inhale lift the left leg up exhale step
it up into your
lunge Warrior
2 so take a second getting there right
it's really about the sensations today
and about the journey and so take your
time as you arrive you're strong
grounded beautiful Warrior
2 so a little work on the
feet goes a long way
then connect to the energetic body
tailbone down front body lips reach both
directions up ground
down big breath in so good for the body
here full body experience energy
radiating then keep the front knee bent
my friends best you can and send the
left fingertips forward up and back as
you can see my right hand's coming
around it can stay on the small of the
back here or reach around to the top top
of the left hip crease keep the front
knee bent as you inhale and
exhale now here we go inhale
straightening through the front leg
inhale extend energy out through the
left fingertips exhale sink deep stay
strong in your back leg inhale
extend and exhale sink
deep nice you got it inhale one last
time and exhale continue this journey
melt it all the way down into your
extended side
angle lean back everyone remember we can
always be
here big breaths strong connection to
the Earth one more breath here you got
it then slowly right fingertips float
down to meet the left we come back to
our lunge we plant The Palms again you
can move through a Vinyasa here or you
can send it straight to downward facing
dog in down dog back to that cleansing
Breath Take a big inhale in through the
nostrils and exhale out through the
mouth great drop the left heel lift the
right leg up
high this time come to Warrior one nice
and strong
reach the fingertips up High Press into
the outer edge of the back foot then
inhale look up exhale rain the
fingertips down stay strong in your
front leg hug energy into the midline
here for
stability I'm going to step back a
little bit here so draw the knuckles
down and away and as you inhale in find
that lift in the heart extension through
the crown as you exhale lift your left
heel up stay soft and bent in the front
knee and we're going to play with a
little warrior 3
so you might just come to he big toe on
the earth keep your focus out in front
neck nice and long inhale in exhale
maybe you begin to lift through the left
inner thigh maybe you come to here right
away or maybe again you're growing this
and so we keep big toe on the
earth stay connected ah the Mind begins
to clear we begin to focus on the
sensations of the body as you lift
through the left inner thigh you can
stay here here you can release with
control to airplane
arms or maybe you take the fingertips
all the way
forward wherever you are full body
experience breathe
deep and then slowly make your way back
to Warrior
1 inhale in smile exhale let it
go back to the lunge optional Vasa here
take it or leave it and to downward
facing
dog beautiful Drop the right heel lift
the left leg up high
inhale exhale stepping through find
Warrior
one take your
time strong
legs when you're ready reach the
fingertips up high ground down to the
shoulders connect to the sensations in
the body today stay
present inhale in exhale rain it
down inner lace this time maybe opposite
thumb on top so the one that feels kind
of weird and Knuckles draw down and away
as we open the
heart welcome that heat that aliveness
that's starting to maybe glisten on your
forehead or your lip stay strong and
grounded to the Earth you got
this inhale look up on an exhale begin
to slowly stay bent in the front leg
lift onto the right big toe again maybe
this is your pose today yes working on
balance stability I'm here I love myself
I got
this and maybe we take it a step further
by softening through the back knee and
beginning to lift up maybe even further
maybe even further lifting up through
the right inner thigh if you are lifted
finding extension through the crown
wherever you are focus on your breath
breath the sensations in your body clear
your mind of any stress of any anxiety
any
worry focus on connecting to your
strength right here right
now so even if you fall you come back
come back to the practice come back to
the midline maybe release the fingertips
with control so resist the slingshot
effect and find air plane
arms and maybe you reach it forward
nice strong breaths everyone wherever
you are be there
fully with your
breath then slowly take your practice
back to Warrior
one inhale look up exhale Shake It Off
take it all the way back down last
chance for Vasa feel free to take it or
leave
it moving through a heart opener if it
feels
good and then we'll all make our way to
Extended child's
pose bring the big toes together melt
the heart
back bring the Palms together and then
up and over the
head gently crawl the elbows forward a
hair stretch through the side body and
the
shoulder take a deep breath
in and exhale let everything go
go surrender here
pronom breathe into the back body close
your
eyes just take a second to bow to the
big
picture to surrender to that which is
out of your
control and to connect to a little sense
of Peace of
Love
[Music]
within slowly we'll drop the fingertips
back to the mat plant The Palms and nice
and easy rise up walk the knees into
Center carefully cross the ankles and
use your fingertips to help guide
yourself all the way back to a seat
and we'll extend the legs out long heels
in line with the
hips um if you're a little bit tight in
the hips in the lower lower body we can
maybe lift the hips up on a blanket or
block here if that feels
good and then we'll inhale reach Towards
the Sky ground down through the tops of
the thighs and then exhale Reaching
Forward so this will look a little
different for everyone it might be here
for
you keeping the neck and the spine nice
and long
it might be
here it might be here so find your
forward
fold again very helpful to lift the hips
up a little bit here eventually find a
sense of surrender here again rounding
through the spine eventually the neck
stretching nice
and yummy here as you bow the
head and bend the knees as generously as
you need to here no need to kind of hit
this perfect little uh yoga shape today
to store any day for that matter matter
but uh find what feels
good find the layer of
breath and then slowly well release and
it comes to lie flat on the
back when you arrive go ahead and hug
the knees into the
chest and then release the left foot to
the ground and the right leg up high
cross the right ankle over the left
interlace the fingertips behind the back
of the left thigh and then bring your
left foot onto an imaginary wall here so
press up against the wall Flex then
we'll begin to squeeze and
pull breathe brething deep here in a
little reclined one-legged pigeon neck
is nice and long so your chin is lifted
see if you can tuck it in a little bit
breathing deep
here great then send the left leg up
high just a little hamstring bonus here
one more
breath and then nice and easy with
control right so again resist the
slingshot effect with control send the
left uh right leg up to meet the left
and then I'm going to reach both
fingertips towards the outer edges and
I'm going to pulse
here keep the shoulders relaxed Palms
facing each other tailbone scooping up
towards the
sky oh my God creaky old
floor oh my God we have a creaky floor
here yay everything's in alignment see
sometimes when you move it just takes a
while right take it to the left pulse
Greek he floor that's for the all all
the the ywa members who have been with
me for a while and to the right here we
go missed that creeky old floor but we
have one here oh my gosh and then back
to Center five 4 3 2 and release yay you
never know when you're going to make new
discoveries right foot to the ground
left leg up
high crossing the
left left ankle over the right inner
lace who would have thought a creaky
floor could bring so much joy to someone
okay Shin parallel to the ceiling flex
your right foot so chances are you know
the shape right but the feet just kind
of head dead hang dead likee so keep a
little aliveness here and then
squeeze again tuck your chin into your
chest and then creaky old floor aside I
I need you to close your eyes and I
would like to invite you to feel
supported your spine supported here the
weight of your body supported by the
Earth keep
breathing and then extend that right leg
up great slowly
unravel left foot joining the right this
time we interlace fingertips behind the
head inhale
in exhale lift the head the neck the
shoulders press into the heels inhale
lower exhale
lift inhale lower exhale lift keep the
elbows wide keep it
going inhale
lower exhale lift extend the thumbs nice
Little Neck hammock here
and three
more scooping the tailbone
up and last one you got
it and release
suasana ah we lit the fire in our belly
after all shimy the shoulders underneath
the heart
here maybe give your little belly a pet
ah
inhale lots of love in exhale close your
eyes begin to allow your breath to
return back to a natural Rhythm
here and then when you're ready we'll
peel the arms out
wide and Slide the legs out long
allow your body to grow heavy even if
you don't have time for a long shavasana
take a second here to let the body
settle and
rest to allow the nutrients of your
practice to seep in to settle
in to notice how you feel
and slowly draw the palms together bring
them to your third
eye and we seal the deal by
saying Namaste which is honoring the
best and most beautiful version of our
self seeing that honoring that in
oneself and then also in others
take good care my
friends choose the light Let It Go
namaste
[Music]